FRANK JONES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER





Profile

Experienced full stack developer with >15 years in the industry. Highly proficient in PHP, MySQL, Javascript, HTML & CSS.

MVC specialist, working primarily with Laravel & Codeigniter.

Works well with stakeholders and product owners to understand the scope of projects and develop digital applications beyond spec and before time.

Has excellent communication skills to inform non-technical players of project progress.



Address

75 Broadsmeath, Tamworth, B77 1DQ



+44 (0) 7565 840 007 frankjones.web@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Electronics

University of Bristol

2006 - 2008

BTECH in Video Production & Media Broadcast

The Institute of Engineering & Technology

2004 - 2005

WORK EXPERIENCE

2020 - 2022

Contracted Developer / Photographer

Faro, Portugal

Soapbox Studio

For the last two years I continued to work for my previous employer on a consultancy basis. Supporting the ongoing development of the CMS and CRM systems I had originally designed.

I also worked as a freelance photographer Europe-wide.

2016 - 2020

Head of Application Development

Düsseldorf, Germany

Matchbird GmbH

- Developed B2B matchmaking application based on companies' SWOT analysis, needs & offers
- Built an advanced CMS for the top 1000 German family companies to rank their vital statistics
- Token authenticated mass email for data verification
- Using tech stack Codeigniter MVC, PHP, MySQL, Git, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap

CODING SKILLS

HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, AJAX, JSON, FFMPEG, MVC Frameworks, Codeigniter, Laravel, Bootstrap, jQuery, Vue

2015 - 2017

Lead Application Developer

Sydney, Australia

Smarteye Pty Ltd.

- Developed application for users to monitor and share video & information about their home security
- Set up payment system using WorldPay
- Designed all the company's print materials
- Server setup & email administration
- Multilingual translation system

KEY DISCIPLINES

- Security (SSL Encryption)
- Server design & deployment
- Database design (MySQL)
- Search engine optimisation
- MVC frameworks
- CSS3/JS libraries
- Google AdSense/Analytics
- Responsive design
- Intuitive design/working pattern
- Project management

REFERENCES

Available on request.

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED...

2014 - 2015 Design Consultant / Production Manager

Bath, UK

RocketMakers

- Designed an application for exhibition attendees to register their interests/goals and make suggestions for real-life meet-ups
- Secure gateway, delegate access only
- Met with clients to understand their needs and delegated to team members

2011 - 2014

Co-Founder / Lead Developer

Bristol, UK

Annotag

- Built a video platform with synchronised PowerPoint slides
- Automated system to export compressed images from PowerPoint slides on upload using VBScript
- Developed automated voice-to-text plugin to generate and display subtitles on video using Dragon Naturally Speaking
- Server-side video encoding using FFMPEG

2008 - 2011

Production Manager / UX UI Designer

Cardiff, UK

Datpresenter

- Built a video platform for conferences to be live streamed
- Built bespoke account management app with ticketing system
- Client-facing tech support & testing
- Created the working documentation and graphical help files for a SaaS video library

2004 - 2008

Broadcast Technician / Front-End Developer

London, UK

Datmedia

- Designed >100 skin templates for video library tool
- Managed video streaming servers in live scenarios
- Testing remote venues for broadcast conditions
- Product testing & reporting to development team